# STEPHEN CHAN

#### **Email**

stephen.albaran.chan @gmail.com

**Phone Number** 

201.780.3777

# **PROFILE**

Full Stack SWE based in Jersey City, NJ. Open to remote and relocation.

# **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** 

Javascript

Python Java

C++

**PHP** 

#### **Frameworks**

Django + Graphene

**VueIS** 

React

#### **Database**

**PostgreSQL** 

#### **Frontend**

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap / Tailwind

### Misc

Git

**Unit Testing** 

GraphQL

Redux - React

Docker

G Cloud

**Adobe Creative Suite** 

Figma

## **Foreign Languages**

Spanish - Advanced Low

## **PROJECTS**

**Gohort** | Ongoing Project

gohort.com

Stack: React + Redux. Jest. Docker. Django. Postgres. Google Cloud. GitHub

Gohort is an early stage travel plan collaboration startup.

- I have taken ownership of design and execution of features using different parts of our stack.
- Features I have implemented include: commit collaboration, client search with Fuse.js, and bugfixes. I am currently redesigning the landing page to increase conversion rates.
- Participate in code reviews through our scrum methodology.

Agua Vida | Ongoing Project

see GitHub

Stack: VueJS. VueX. Java. GitHub.

Agua Vida automates the calculation of complex chlorine formulas.

• Envisioned, designed, implemented, and published the app and the SPA during my time in the Peace Corps (as a personal project).

**JASS Manual for PC Peru** 

InDesign, XD, Illustrator | Ongoing Project

Served as one of the authors and as the principal editor for the WASH program manual, a new 200 page guide to working with JASS and water systems in Peru. I am currently responsible for creating, collecting, and editing content for this ongoing effort.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## US Peace Corps, Peru

Water, Sanitation, and Hygiene Volunteer

Mar 2018 - Mar 2020

Trained rural 8 water community operators on chlorination and water system technologies, which improved the water quality for communities of over 2000 residents. Worked specifically with non-technical operators.

## The Vector Student Newspaper, NJIT

Editor in Chief

May 2016 - May 2017

Manager of weekly newspaper's 5 person editorial team across several disciplines, pushing quality content every issue and managing design projects. Further analyzed data to refine visual style and content.

Interim Web and Multimedia Editor

Feb 2013 - May 2013

Operated the newspaper's website as the main administrator. Used WordPress and its analytics software to plan content releases throughout the week to grow page views. Improved user experience on webpage.

# **EDUCATION**

New Jersey Institute of Technology

Newark, NJ

B.S. in Computer Engineering

Graduated August 2017

# TRAINING

**Associate Collegiate Press** 

Design/Redesign Workshop Summer 2015